<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter version="5.0" xml:id="use.configuration" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook">
  <title>How to use</title>
  <para>This section explains, how to use the .netbridge.</para>
  <section>
    <title>Introducation</title>
    <para> This section explains how to use the .netbridge. All the domains and connectors in
      OpenEngSB are written in java. So if you want to use a onther language like for example C# to
      communicate with the domain, you have to translate all the commands from java to C# and back.
      If you had to do that for every connector, it would be a lot of work and it would be difficult
      to handel changes on versions. For this problem, the .netbridge has been created. It registers
      a connector and profites the functions, to invoke methods in the domain.</para>
    <para>In the <xref xlink:href="#Domaindecription"/>, the domain description will be
      explained, which the .Net bridge need as dll. How to create the dll is explaned in <xref xlink:href="#WSDLTODLLPLUGIN"/>
      or <xref xlink:href="#WSDLTODLLNoPLUGIN"/> and in the <xref xlink:href="#Example"/> it is explaned, how to invoke a method. In the last
      Section, a example of the .Net Bridge is shown.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Domaindecription">
    <title>Domain description</title>
    <para> To communicate with a domain, it is required to get the interfacedesciptions. These have
      the nameconvention: "DomainName"Domain and "DomainName"DomainEvents. When building the domain,
      these information are encoded in a WSDL. In other words, after building there are two WSDL's,
      which descripes how to communicate with this domain. These informations have to be translated
      to dll and included into C#. There are two ways to do this, which are explaned in the
      following paragraphs </para>
  </section>

  <section xml:id="WSDLTODLLPLUGIN">
    <title>Wsdl to dll (With the maven plugin)</title>
    <para><emphasis role="bold"><emphasis role="italic">To use this plugin, NPanday is
          regired!</emphasis></emphasis></para>
    <para> To have an easy and fast way, to build the dll from a wsdl, a maven plugin has been
      introduced. The plugin has the following structur:</para>
    <para><programlisting>&lt;plugin>
  &lt;groupId>org.openengsb.plugin&lt;/groupId>
  &lt;artifactId>generate-cs-dll&lt;/artifactId>
  &lt;version>VersionNumber&lt;/version>
  &lt;configuration>
    &lt;npanday_setting>${user.home}\.m2\npanday-settings.xml&lt;/npanday_setting>
    &lt;wsdl_location>Location to the WSDL FILE&lt;/wsdl_location>
  &lt;/configuration>
&lt;/plugin></programlisting></para>
    <para>After maven install, the corresponding dll is in the target folder.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="WSDLTODLLNoPLUGIN">
    <title>Wsdl to dll (Without the plugin)</title>
    <para>If you do not want to install NPanday, you can generate the dll manually. First you need
      the location of the WSDL from the corresponding domain. Then you can use the following command
      in the "Visual studio command Prompt" </para>
    <para><code>wsdl /serverInterface namespace_name wsdl_location </code>. </para>
    <para>After this step, a <emphasis role="italic">cs</emphasis> file has been created. This
        <emphasis role="italic">cs</emphasis> file has to bee compiled to a dll. This can be done by
      executing the following command in the "Visual studio command Prompt"</para>
    <para><code>csc.exe /target:library  cs_file_path</code></para>
    <para>Finnally, the dll has been created.</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">Note:</emphasis> If you do not have the "Visual studio command
      Prompt" then you can browse with the Windows Command prompt (cmd) to the wsdl.exe/csc.exe
      location and execute it like meanched before. These filese can also be downloaded from the
      web.</para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Connector">
    <title>Register a connector and invoke methods</title>
    <para>There are two ways, to get a instance of the factory, which is used to get the
      eventhandler. The first way, the OpenEngSB version is indicted. This call would looke like
      this:</para>
    <para><code>DomainFactoryProvider.GetDomainFactoryInstance("3.0.0")</code></para>
    <para>The other way, is by indicating the URL, whcih returns the version number. This could look
      like this:</para>
    <para><code>DomainFactoryProvider.GetDomainFactoryInstance(new Uri("http://localhost:8090"));</code></para>
    <para>In the next step, the methods for the answer from the Domain has to be specified. The
      methods, which can be invoked by the domain are defined in the "DomainName"Domain and have to
      be implementend in a class (inherite from the corresponding dll). Furthermore, the specified
      class has to inherite the partial class <emphasis role="italic"
        >RegistrationFunctions</emphasis>. This partial class contains the function for the
      registration calls from the domain. These methods can be overriden, if desired.  With the
      following call, the bridge will be registrating the bridge as connector:</para>
    <para><code>factory.RegisterDomainService(destination, localDomain, domainName);</code></para>
    <para>Last but not least, the a proxy can be created, to invoke methods on the domain. This is
      done by invoking the following method:</para>
    <para><code>factory.getEventhandler&lt;"DomainName"DomainEvents>(destination);</code></para>
    <para>Now it is possible, to invoke methods on the domain. For example:</para>
    <para><code>remotedomain.raiseTestStartEvent(TestStartEvent);</code></para>
  </section>
  <section xml:id="Example">
    <title>Example of the netbridge, with the OpenEngSB Test-domain</title>
    <para> The library <emphasis role="italic">ServiceTestConsole</emphasis> in the .Net Bridge
      contains the example, to connect with the Test-domain. This exanple has the following
      stucture</para>
    <para><inlinemediaobject>
        <imageobject>
          <imagedata fileref="graphics/Example1.png"/>
        </imageobject>
      </inlinemediaobject></para>
  </section>
</chapter>
